Hays mss., 1900-1985 LMC 2671
Lilly Library
Hays mss.
1900-1985
Lilly Library
Hays, Will H. (Will Harrison), 1879-1954.
Hays, Will H. (Will Harrison), 1915-
LMC 2671
27 Boxes
The Hays mss., 1900-1985, consists of the papers of Will Hays, Sr., Republican politician and the first President of the Motion Picture Producers and Distributors of America (MPPDA), and his son Will Hays, Jr., author and Indiana mayor.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Will Hays, 1879-1954, was a Republican politician and the first president of the Motion Picture Producers and Distributors of America (MPPDA). The so-called "Hays Code," which provided movie studios with a set of moral guidelines for self-censorship, bears his name.
Hays was born in Sullivan, Indiana in 1879. He served as the Chairman of the Republican National Committee from 1918-1921, managing the successful campaign of Warren G. Harding for the presidency in 1920. Following Harding's election, Hays was appointed Postmaster General in 1921, a post he held until 1922, when he resigned in order to become the first President of the Motion Picture Producers and Distributors of America (MPPDA). During his tenure, Hays established the Motion Picture Production Code, popularly known as the Hays Code, which provided a set of moral guidelines for self-censorship of US movies, forbidding depictions of such things as profanity, miscegenation, childbirth, ridicule of religion, and "sex perversion." Hays retired from the post in 1945, returning to Sullivan, where he died on March 7, 1954.
Will Hays, Jr., 1915-2000, was an author and Indiana politician. Hays was born in Indianapolis in 1915. He attended Wabash College and Yale Law School. In 1949, he wrote the musical You're My Everything, and in the 1950s, he was a scriptwriter for the television program "This Is Your Life." He served two terms as mayor of Crawfordsville, Indiana from 1965-1973.
Scope and Content Note
Collection consists of materials related to Hays political career. Memoirs includes drafts, notes, research materials related to The Memoirs of Will H. Hays (published in 1955). Writings include those of both Will Hays, Sr. and Will Hays, Jr. (born December 11, 1915, also in Sullivan, IN), including an unpublished draft based on their relationship written by the son. (Will Hays, Jr. became involved in the movie business as well: His musical You're My Everything was produced in 1949, and he wrote numerous scripts for the television show This is Your Life.) The Chaney Digest was compiled by Dirrelle Chaney, a longtime associate of Hays and owner of the Sullivan Union, a weekly newspaper in Sullivan, IN, who worked for Hays when he was Postmaster General. The Digest summarizes important events and Hays' activities. Diaries include Hays's Postmaster General calendar. Genealogical materials include charts of the Hays family tree. Miscellaneous materials feature a Ball State University dissertation, "Will H. Hays: Republican Politician," written by Richard Joseph Cinclair.
Correspondents include John Boettinger, Calvin Coolidge, Thomas Edison, Warren G. Harding, Herbert Hoover, Henry Cabot Lodge, Benito Mussolini, Eleanor Roosevelt, Franklin Roosevelt, Theodore Roosevelt, William Taft, and a photograph of the first manned flight at Kitty Hawk, North Carolina, 17 Dec 1903, autographed by Orville Wright.
Hays also received numerous photographs from Hollywood movie stars. Autographed portraits include Jimmie Adams, Mary Astor, Viola Banky, Warner Baxter, Noah Beery, Monte Blue, Clara Bow, Mary Brian, Clive Brook, Neal Burns, Eddie Cantor, Lon Chaney, Sr., Syd Chaplin, Ruth Clifford, Ronald Colman, Virginia de Corbin, Maria Corda, Dolores Costello, Bebe Daniels, Dorothy Devore, Billy Dooley, Billie Dove, Jack Duffy, Louise Fazenda, W. C. Fields, Lillian Gish, Lawrence Gray, Corinne Griffith, Raymond Griffith, Bill Hart, Raymond Hatton, Lloyd Hughes, Bill Irving, Emil Jannings, Osa Johnson, Leatrice Joy, Alice Joyce, Buster Keaton, Donald Keith, Doris Kenyon, Natalie Kingston, Lupino Lane, Harry Langdon, Dorothy Mackaill, Tim McCoy, Victor McGlagen, Tom Mix, Jack Mulhall, Charlie Murray, Molly O'Day, Mary Pickford, William Powell, Esther Ralston, Carroll Reece, Donald Reed, Irene Rich, Will Rogers, Chic Sale, Malcolm Sebastian (a.k.a. "Big Boy"), Vera Steadman, Gloria Swanson, Constance Talmadge, Estelle Taylor, Shirley Temple, Virginia Valli, Bobby Vernon, Paul Vincenti, Count Felix vonLuckner, Alice White, Loretta Young, and Adolph Zukor.
Note on Indexing Term - "Motion picture film": The collection includes documents from Hays's time as the President of the Motion Picture Producers and Distributors of America.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series: I. Memoirs, II. Writings, III. Photographs, IV. Chaney Digest, V. Diaries, VI. Genealogical Materials, VII. Personal and Professional Files, VIII. Correspondence, IX. Articles, X. Audio-Visual Materials, and XI. Miscellaneous.
Series II. Writings is divided into the following subseries: Articles by Will Hays, Speeches by Will Hays, Sr., and Writings by Will Hays, Jr.
Series VII. Personal and Professional Files is divided into subseries on Indiana, Politics, Military, and Motion Pictures.
Acquisition Information
Acquired: 2009
Motion picture film; Politicians --Indiana --Archives.; Hays, Will H. (Will Harrison), 1879-1954.; Hays, Will H. (Will Harrison), 1915-; Coolidge, Calvin, 1872-1933.; Edison, Thomas A. (Thomas Alva), 1847-1931.; Harding, Warren G. (Warren Gamaliel), 1865-1923.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1850-1924.; Mussolini, Benito, 1883-1945.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919.; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930.; Wright, Orville, 1871-1948.; Astor, Mary, 1906-1987.; Bow, Clara, 1905-1965.; Chaney, Lon, 1883-1930.; Gish, Lillian, 1893-1993.; Keaton, Buster, 1895-1966.; Motion Picture Producers and Distributors of America
- Memoirs (Box 1)
  General
  Memoirs are organized into "parts" and "chapters" according to the organization of the published book. Materials relating to the entire book appear first, followed by materials relating to each part or chapter. Titles are offered for clarification. There are no materials pertaining to chapters 12-16.
  - General Research and Notes (Box 1)
    Transcripts were copied from audio-recorded discs. These discs are not in the collection.
    - Transcript of dictation from discs 1-42 and index, bound (Box 1)
    - Transcript of dictation from discs 1-10 (Box 1)
    - Transcript of dictation from discs 11-20 (Box 1)
    - Transcript of dictation from discs 21-30 (Box 1)
    - Transcript of dictation from discs 31-42 (Box 1)
    - Transcript of dictation, index (Box 1)
    - Transcript of dictation from discs 1-5 (Box 1)
    - Transcript of dictation from discs 6-15 (Box 1)
    - Transcript of dictation from discs 16-22 (Box 1)
    - Transcript of dictation from discs 23-30 (Box 1)
    - Transcript of dictation from discs 31-45 (Box 1)
    - Transcript of dictation, index (Box 1)
    - Transcript of dictation from discs 1-8 (Box 1)
    - Transcript of dictation from discs 1-24 "6th copy" (Box 1)
    - Transcript of dictation from discs 25-36 "6th copy" (Box 1)
    - Transcript of dictation from discs 37-42 "6th copy" (Box 1)
    - Transcript of dictation from special discs (4 folders) (Box 1)
    - Edited dictation (Box 1)
    - Edited dictation, Motion Picture (Box 1)
    - Edited dictation, Post Master General (Box 1)
    - Edited dictation, National Chairman (Box 1)
    - Edited dictation, Indiana State Chairman (Box 1)
    - Edited dictation, Indiana Defense Council (Box 1)
    - Edited dictation, College (Box 1)
    - Edited dictation, Young Lawyer (Box 1)
    - Edited dictation, various topics (Box 1)
    - Dictation, notes and suggestions (Box 1)
    - Association of Motion Picture Producers (AMPP) Minutes, discs 1-20, (3 copies) (Box 1)
    - AMPP Minutes, discs 21-32, (3 copies) (Box 1)
    - AMPP Minutes, summary, (2 copies) (Box 1)
    - AMPP Minutes, discs 4-10 (Box 2)
    - AMPP Minutes, discs 11-20 (Box 2)
    - AMPP Minutes, discs 21-32 (Box 2)
    - AMPP Minutes, California, discs 4-15 (Box 2)
    - AMPP Minutes, California, discs 16-25 (Box 2)
    - AMPP Minutes, California, discs 26-32 (Box 2)
    - AMPP Minutes, New York (Box 2)
    - AMPP Minutes, 1922-1925 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence with Fred Niblo, Jr., 1948 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence with Fred Niblo, Jr., Jan-May 1949 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence with Fred Niblo, Jr., June-Dec 1949 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence with Fred Niblo, Jr., 1950 (Box 2)
    - Drafts, memos, and correspondence from Fred Niblo, Jr., removed from notebook, (7 folders) (Box 2)
    - E.B. Chamberlain, running commentary on drafts from Fred Niblo, Jr. (Box 2)
    - Memos (Box 2)
    - Memos, 22 May 1952 (Box 2)
    - Memos, from E.B. Chamberlain to Will H. Hays (Box 2)
    - Correspondence between E.B. Chamberlain and Chaney (Box 2)
    - Reports and other writings by E.B. Chamberlain, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Items from Julia Kelly (Box 2)
    - Chaney Digest References (Box 2)
    - JHH diary excerpts (Box 2)
    - Newspaper biographies of WHH (Box 2)
    - Articles about WHH (Box 2)
    - Articles about WHH, notes (Box 2)
    - Masonic Speech (Box 2)
    - Genealogy, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Timeline, 1913 (Box 2)
    - Timeline, 1914 (Box 2)
    - Diary of Western Trip, 1918 (Box 2)
    - Table of Contents of Souvenir File (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous research, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Research, originally for Part 5, used for others chapters, (10 folders) (Box 3)
    - Proposed chapter outline (Box 3)
    - Bibliography (Box 3)
    - Indexes (Box 3)
    - Index to drafts, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Record book plan, removed from notebook (Box 3)
    - Bibliography, removed from notebook (Box 3)
    - Chronology, removed from notebook (Box 3)
    - Memos, removed from notebook (Box 3)
    - References, removed from notebook (Box 3)
    - Big themes, removed from notebook (Box 3)
    - Names and Genealogy, removed from notebook (Box 3)
    - Foreword draft (Box 3)
    - Publisher's proof, with edits, (7 folders) (Box 3)
    - Publisher's proof, with edits, continued, (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - Part 1: Youth (Box 4)
    - Research, Correspondence, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Research, Sullivan, Indiana (Box 4)
    - Research, Cain Family Souvenirs (Box 4)
    - Research, Thomas Family (Box 4)
    - Research, "I Learned a Lot from the Folks Back Home", article written by WHH (Box 4)
    - Memo, from Notebook 1 (Box 4)
    - Outlines of chapter 1-5 (Box 4)
    - Handwritten draft, (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - Draft, chapters 1-5, RHM copy (Box 4)
    - Draft (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous and unused (Box 4)
    - Chapter 1: From Generation to Generation (Box 4)
      - Second draft (Box 4)
      - Third draft, from notebook 1 (Box 4)
    - Chapter 2: My Hoosier Tradition (Box 4)
      - Second draft (Box 4)
      - Second draft, from notebook 1 (Box 4)
    - Chapter 3: From Six to Sixteen (Box 4)
      - Handwritten draft (Box 4)
      - Second draft, from notebook 1 (Box 4)
    - Chapter 4: Wabash College, 1896-1900 (Box 4)
      - Second draft, from notebook 1 (Box 4)
    - Chapter 5: Going to Work (Box 4)
      - Draft (Box 4)
      - Draft, from notebook 1 (Box 4)
  - Part 2: Law and Local Politics (Box 4)
    - Research, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Notes (Box 4)
    - Notes, chapters 6-7 (Box 4)
    - Outline (Box 4)
    - Revisions by Wythe Williams (Box 4)
    - Chapter 6: "Willie—Master in Politics" (Box 4)
      - Outline (Box 4)
      - First draft, 12 Jan 1949 (Box 4)
      - Annotated first draft (Box 4)
      - Draft, from notebook 1, (2 folders) (Box 4)
      - Draft (Box 4)
    - Chapter 7: Eventually the Republican Party (Box 5)
      - Handwritten outline (Box 5)
      - Outline, (2 copies) (Box 5)
      - Notes (Box 5)
      - First draft (Box 5)
      - Annotated first draft (Box 5)
      - Draft, from notebook 2, (3 folders) (Box 5)
      - Draft (Box 5)
    - Chapter 8: Indiana State Council of Defense (Box 5)
      - Outlines, (2 folders) (Box 5)
      - Notes (Box 5)
      - Handwritten draft, (2 folders) (Box 5)
      - First draft (Box 5)
      - Draft, from notebook 2, (2 folders) (Box 5)
      - Draft (Box 5)
      - Draft, proofread by RHM (Box 5)
    - Chapter 9: Shooting the Bull Moose (Box 5)
      - Notes (Box 5)
      - Handwritten notes and draft (Box 5)
      - First draft (Box 5)
      - Draft, from notebook 2 (Box 5)
      - Draft (Box 5)
  - Part 3: National Politics, 1918-1922 (Box 5)
    - Summary of by Julia Kelly, 1918-1921 (Box 5)
    - Handwritten outline (Box 5)
    - Outline, 5 Feb 1948 (Box 5)
    - Outline, 31 May 1948; (2 copies) (Box 5)
    - Handwritten notes (Box 5)
    - Notes, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Original draft, (4 folders) (Box 5)
    - Draft, chapters 10-13 (Box 6)
    - Draft, chapters 14-20 (Box 6)
    - Draft, chapters 21-23 (Box 6)
    - Revisions by Wythe Williams (Box 6)
    - Discarded draft, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Chapter 10: Chosen National Chairman (Box 6)
      - Notes (Box 6)
    - Chapter 11: The Task of Organizing (Box 6)
      - Research materials (Box 6)
    - Chapter 17: A Treaty without Peace (Box 6)
      Note: Materials for chapters 12-16 found under "Part 3".
      - Research, Addresses (Box 6)
      - Research, Address by Senator Kellogg (Box 6)
      - Research, Address by Senator Underwood (Box 6)
      - Research, All Rational People (Box 6)
      - Research, Articles, (2 folders) (Box 6)
      - Research, Articles, "League of Nations", by Oswald F. Schuette (Box 6)
      - Research, Articles, New York Times (Box 6)
      - Research, Articles, "Tragedy of Versailles", by William C. Bullitt (Box 6)
      - Research, Articles, "The U.S. and the League of Nations", by Denna Frank Fleming (Box 6)
      - Research, Articles, "When is a President Disabled?", by Charles M. Thomas (Box 6)
      - Research, Campaign Speech (Box 6)
      - Research, Correspondence with Mrs. Jean Tomlinson (Box 6)
      - Research, Court of International Justice (Box 6)
      - Research, League of Nations (Box 6)
      - Research, League of Nations Covenant (Box 6)
      - Research, Lodge's Reservations (Box 6)
      - Research, Politics vs. Peace (Box 6)
      - Research, Repetition of History (Box 6)
      - Research, Senate Debates, (3 folders) (Box 6)
      - Research, Statements (Box 6)
      - Research, Taft Speeches (Box 6)
      - Chronology (Box 6)
      - Notes (Box 6)
      - Index (Box 6)
      - Early draft titled "Story of a Tragedy", part 1 (Box 6)
      - Early draft titled "Story of a Tragedy", part 2 (Box 6)
      - Early draft titled "Story of a Tragedy", part 1-2 (Box 6)
      - Early drafts (Box 6)
      - Draft, early short form by WW (Box 6)
      - Draft, 30 Sept 1947 (Box 6)
      - Draft, (2 copies) (Box 6)
      - Draft, with edits (Box 6)
      - Working copy, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Chapter 18: 1919—Endings and Beginnings (Box 7)
      - Research materials (Box 7)
    - Chapter 20: Back to Normalcy" and Woman Suffrage (Box 7)
      - Note: Materials for chapter 19 found under "Part 3". (Box 7)
      - Draft (Box 7)
      - Draft, first part of chapter (Box 7)
    - Chapter 21: The 1920 Campaign (Box 7)
      - First draft (Box 7)
      - Second draft notes (Box 7)
    - Chapter 22: Humanizing the Postal Service (Box 7)
      - Research, clippings (Box 7)
      - Notes and research (Box 7)
      - Notes, (3 folders) (Box 7)
      - First part, handwritten draft (Box 7)
      - First part, three drafts (Box 7)
      - Second part, handwritten draft (Box 7)
      - Second part, draft (Box 7)
      - Draft (Box 7)
    - Chapter 23: Trucks, Tubes and Mail Robbers (Box 7)
      - Original draft, marked (Box 7)
    - Chapter 24: Live and Help Live (Box 7)
      - Aviation research, (7 folders) (Box 7)
      - Aviation research, clippings, (2 folders) (Box 7)
      - Aviation research, Meeting (Box 7)
      - Notes, (3 folders) (Box 7)
      - Drafts, 13 Aug 1947; 3 Sept 1947; 5 Nov 1947 (Box 7)
  - Part 4: Motion Pictures, 1922-1945 (Box 7)
    - Research (4 folders) (Box 7)
    - Research, Harry Chandler (Box 7)
    - Research, Chandler-Hall (Box 7)
    - Research, Politics during Movie Period (Box 7)
    - Research, Zukor dinner (Box 7)
    - Research, Production Code Conference, Book 1 (Box 8)
    - Research, Production Code Conference, Book 2 (Box 8)
    - Research, Production Code Conference, copy 2 (Box 8)
    - References (Box 8)
    - Indexes (Box 8)
    - Draft, chapters 24-27 (Box 8)
    - Draft, chapters 28-30 (Box 8)
    - Draft, chapters 31-33 (Box 8)
    - Draft, chapters 34-36 (Box 8)
    - Chapter 25: The First Year in Hollywood, 1922-1923 (Box 8)
      - Outline and draft (Box 8)
    - Chapter 26: The "Silent" Reaches Its Zenith (), March 1923-August 1926 (Box 8)
      - Outline, notes and draft (Box 8)
    - Chapter 27: Sound Arrives (August 6, 1926-June 6, 1930) (Box 8)
      - Outline and drafts (Box 8)
    - Chapter 28: The Production Code (Box 8)
      - Notes and draft (Box 8)
      - First draft (Box 8)
    - Chapter 29: Full Steam Ahead (July 6, 1929-March 29, 1937) (Box 8)
      - Outline and draft (Box 8)
      - Draft (Box 8)
      - "Code" essay, Dec 1953 (Box 8)
    - Chapter 30: Before the Storm (1937-1941) (Box 8)
      - "Neely Bill" Correspondence, (3 folders) (Box 8)
      - Outline and draft (Box 8)
    - Chapter 31: Foreign Relations (Box 8)
      - Research (Box 8)
      - Research and notes (Box 8)
      - Notes, (2 folders) (Box 8)
      - Outline and draft, (2 copies) (Box 8)
      - Draft (Box 8)
    - Chapter 32: Motion Pictures and the War (1941-1945) (Box 8)
      - Research, (2 folders) (Box 8)
      - Early outline and draft (Box 8)
      - Outline and draft (Box 8)
    - Chapter 33: The Presbyterian Pension Fund (Box 9)
      - Research, (8 folders) (Box 9)
      - Research, catalog of films (Box 9)
      - Research, Motion pictures in education (Box 9)
      - Memos (Box 9)
      - Outline and draft (Box 9)
    - Chapter 34: In the Fullness of Time (Box 9)
      - Outline and draft (Box 9)
- Writings (Box 9)
  Scope and Contents
  Divided into writings by Will Hays, Sr., and Will Hays, Jr.
  - Articles by Will Hays (Box 9)
    - "The American Motion Picture", published in The Film Daily vol. 104, no. 31., 13 Aug 1953 (Box 9)
    - "The Black Horse and His Rider", unpublished handwritten manuscript about Paul Revere (Box 9)
    - "Discussion of the Negro Problem", bound typescript (Box 9)
    - "John T. Hays", unpublished short biography (Box 9)
    - "William Harrison Hays", unpublished short biography (Box 9)
    - "Humanizing the Post Office", published in The Outlook, 1 June 1921 (Box 9)
    - "It's Up To Every American", published in Liberty, 9 Nov 1940 (Box 9)
    - "Shall We Kill Our President?", published in Hearst's International Magazine, Oct 1923; (2 copies) (Box 9)
    - "Things do not Happen", draft (Box 9)
    - "E. Darwin Thomas, Jr.", unpublished short biography (Box 9)
    - A Book of Advice, with a page by Will Hays, inscription to Will Hays Jr. on title page, 24 Nov 1923 (Box 23)
  - Speeches by Will Hays, Sr. (Box 9)
    - Drafts, (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - Excerpts (Box 9)
    - Speech indexes, 1907-1918 (Box 26)
    - Speeches by Will H. Hays: bound volume, 1900-1906 (Box 26)
    - Speeches by Will H. Hays: bound volume, 1907-1918 (Box 26)
  - Writings by Will Hays Jr. (Box 9)
    - Back Trail to Red Bluff script, bound, 1959 (Box 9)
    - Dragon Watch Chapters 1-19, bound, with edits (Box 9)
    - Dragon Watch Chapters 20-29, bound, with edits (Box 10)
    - Dragon Watch Chapters 30-end, bound, with edits (Box 10)
    - This is Your Life"DeVere Frank Backer", bound script (Box 10)
    - This is Your Life"Stephen Boyd", bound script (Box 10)
    - This is Your Life"Rossano Brazzi", bound script (Box 10)
    - This is Your Life"Dick Clark", bound script (Box 10)
    - This is Your Life"Charles Coburn", bound script (Box 10)
    - This is Your Life"Henry C. Conner", bound script (Box 10)
    - This is Your Life"Mrs. Sidonie Flacco", bound script (Box 10)
    - This is Your Life"Mrs. Betty Hahn", bound script (Box 10)
    - This is Your Life"Selma Herbert", bound script (Box 10)
    - This is Your Life"Bea Knight", bound script (Box 10)
    - This is Your Life"Mervly LeRoy", bound script (Box 10)
    - This is Your Life"Serge Obolensky", bound script (Box 10)
    - This is Your Life"Dr. Martin Palmer", bound script (Box 10)
    - This is Your Life"Viola Pogson", bound script (Box 11)
    - This is Your Life"Mira Slovak", bound script (Box 11)
    - This is Your Life"Rita Webb Smith", bound script (Box 11)
    - This is Your Life"Calla Varner", bound script (Box 11)
    - This is Your Life"Count Felix von Luckner", bound script (Box 11)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, 1919-1922 (Box 11)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, 1923 (Box 11)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, 1924 (Box 11)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, Jan-July 1925 (Box 11)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, Aug-Dec 1925 (Box 11)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, Jan-June 1926 (Box 11)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, July-Dec 1926 (Box 11)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, Jan-April 1927 (Box 11)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, May-Dec 1927 (Box 11)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, Jan-June 1928 (Box 11)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, July-Dec 1928 (Box 11)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, Jan-June 1929 (Box 11)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, July-Dec 1929 (Box 11)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, Jan-April 1930; (2 copies) (Box 11)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, May-July 1930 (Box 11)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, Aug-Dec 1930; (2 copies) (Box 11)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, Jan-June 1931; (2 copies) (Box 11)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, July-Aug 1931; (2 copies) (Box 11)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, Sept-Dec 1931; (2 copies) (Box 11)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, Jan-Mar 1932; (2 copies) (Box 11)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, April-Dec 1932; (2 copies) (Box 12)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, Jan-May 1933; (2 copies) (Box 12)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, June-Dec 1933; (2 copies) (Box 12)
    - Untitled Manuscript, research, correspondence copies, 1934-1941; (2 copies) (Box 12)
    - Untitled Manuscript, edited letters, (11 folders) (Box 12)
    - Untitled Manuscript, Original manuscript of 1981 revision, (6 folders) (Box 12)
    - Untitled Manuscript, Revision Work Copy, (5 folders) (Box 12)
    - You're My Everything Draft (Box 13)
    - You're My Everything Discards (Box 13)
    - You're My Everything script, 4, Oct 1948 (Box 13)
    - You're My Everything script, 12 Nov 1948 (Box 13)
    - Loose on the Wind scrapbook, includes clippings and correspondence, (2 volumes) (Box 20)
    - Loose on the Wind draft, pp. 1-100 (Box 26)
    - Loose on the Wind draft, pp. 101-200 (Box 26)
    - Loose on the Wind draft, pp. 201-300 (Box 26)